# **SAMMIE CHESTON**

0423 483 774 | 2/10 TOWNSEND STREET | 5063 | PARKSIDE SA | SAMMIECHESTON@PROTONMAIL.COM

# Web Development - Digital Marketing - Graphics - iPhotographer - Audio / Video Production

### **SUMMARY**

Digital marketer with more than 10+ years of media marketing and production experience in the entertainment industry. Broad knowledge of content creation for social media, web, digital signage, email and SMS. Proficient at creating and implementing client-centred, aimed at enhancing brand awareness and presence.

### **CAREER HISTORY**

## 2019 to Current, (Volunteer) Digital Media Marketing, Salvation Army Unley, Unley

- Increased congregation from 100 in-house worshipers to more than 700 members on Facebook, both internationally and locally starting from the initial start of COVID lockdowns.
- Co-hosting meetings, digital-marketing planning including interpreting web, Facebook/ Instagram/Twitter and YouTube; also implemented SEM and SEO strategies. Prepared digital marketing analytical reports to be issued to the Director of Salvo Unley.
- Review submissions such as prints, web & social media content, and electronic direct mail newsletters for continuity and quality control, in addition to editing video/streamed content while always seeking new innovative ways to communicate.
- Created landing page by using JAM Stack architecture and where parishioners can view Facebook live streams without having a Facebook account. Produced and directed Red Shield Appeal fundraising campaign video.
- Contributing team member, creating and promoting awareness events such as coffee connect and coffee on wheels. Purpose of events is to build trust and inform the community of who we are, what we do, and where we are.

## 2013-Current, Marketing Communications & Ops Manager, Bitcoin Exchange, Singapore

- Reports to the General Manager. Leads 11 staff with four based in Singapore and Philippines.
- Interlinked Chatbot AI database to the social media platforms main website, phone services and bitcoin ATM. This helped create market predictability, which increased sales by more than 46 per cent by forecasting market behaviours.
- Built landing pages that funnelled focus and monitored visitors site activities to determine outreach approach such as YouTube, Podcast and Facebook short video/ audio snippets.
- Implemented '360-Flow' data collection, creating consistent cross-platform user experience and brand continuity. This drove brand loyalty and matched customers to events based on their interests.
- Designed mobile app UX and UI, which matched the website and Chatbot, and created a 66 per cent reduction in customer questions due to improved clarity.
- Designed studies surveys and behaviour analysis to determine market segment definitions. Created enhanced predictability of customers selling and buying of bitcoins.

# **SAMMIE CHESTON**

## 2/10 TOWNSEND STREET | 5063 | PARKSIDE SA | SAMMIECHESTON@PROTONMAIL.COM

## 2009 to 2011, Residential Advisor, UniLodge @ Metro Adelaide, Adelaide

- Liaison between residents and building administrators while creating a sense of connectedness and union within the residential building.
- Developed marketing strategy for group activity program entitled Community Sprit to increase memberships.
- Increased brand value by encouraging word-of-mouth promotion of great community living environment with thyme of building lifelong friendships.

## 2010 to 2010, Business Consultant, Royal Automobile Association, Adelaide

- Developed an effective brochure logistic system to enhance agents' sells and provided sufficient service for customers through by research and data crunching.
- Improved distribution and storage efficiency to be an efficient to for agents and greater accessibility for the consumer.
- Created long-term strategic synergies that are a strategic fit for future alignment in a fast changing business environment by use of API for trend reporting from Google.

## 2007 to 2008, Assistant to Producer (Films) HBO, Hollywood, LA

- Implemented promotional planning by collocating with content team on press kits, selecting outlets such as late shows and in-person appearances, branding development, and hosted brainstorming marketing meetings.
- Managed brand partnerships, social competitions, auctioned props as media blitz, used niche social platforms, pre-roll advertising, persona marketing, and staged publicity stunts.

### 2004 to 2007, Assistant to Producer, (Films) Brown Bag Films, New York

- Collaborated with marketing teams in multiple locations, and managed logistics of videographers and photographers.
- Identified and sourced production crew and equipment and props; also finalised contractual administrative requirements.
- Collaborated with post production team to select clips for movie trailers and developed campaign strategies.

## 2001 to 2003, Promotions and Marketing, (Distributor) Sony Music, New York

- Marketing: Using data to determine tour dates, venues, targeted audience, and local trends. Therefore able to determine overall sells strategy.
- Promotional materials: Organised photos shoots, scout for video locations and hiring of production crew and finalising administrative requirements for video production. In addition to hiring graphic artists and designers to create the promotion package.
- Promotional Tours: Sourcing promotional street teams and sending marketing material ahead of performing artist.

### 1999 to 2001, Producer and Promotions, (House Music) Trax Records, Chicago

- Produced artists to give music creative direction in the recording studio.
- Planned marketing strategies that included street teams and digital marketing campaign.
- Managed the production of marketing material for artists new recorded releases. In which includes photos, videos, graphics, and prints.

# **SAMMIE CHESTON**

## 2/10 TOWNSEND STREET | 5063 | PARKSIDE SA | SAMMIECHESTON@PROTONMAIL.COM

## **EDUCATION**

- 2022, Southern Hemisphere Space Studies Program, Certification, International Space University / UniSA, Adelaide
- 2021, The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing, Certification (ID# 8DXF3LLTF), Google
- 2009-2011, Master of Business Administration (Business In China), University of South Australia, Adelaide
- 1999-2002, Bachelor of Arts(Media Management/Music Business), Columbia College Chicago, Chicago

### TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

- Language: HTML 5, Javascript, CSS, Python, MySQL
- Google: Tag Management, Analytics
- Social Media: Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, LinkedIn, TicTok, Club House, Youtube, WeChat, Tencent QQ, Reddit, Github, Stack Overflow
- Software: Office 360, Keynote, iMovie, Motion, Ableton, Photoshop, Premiere, Salesforce, Canva

### **PROFESSIONALISM**

- √ Business analysis, contract management, research and process modelling acumen
- ✓ Comprehensive international and local project management experience
- ✓ Continuous learning and integration experience
- ✓ Scrum and Kanban project experience
- ✓ Organises workloads effectively amongst competing priorities
- ✓ Develops procedures to streamline operations and enhance revenue performance
- ✓ Builds productive and positive relationships with workers and contractors
- ✓ Accurate and detailed administration and documentation experience
- √ Works under broad direction in a team environment
- ✓ Demonstrates integrity and confidentiality

# **VOLUNTEERISM**

- Digital Media Marketing, Salvation Army, Unley
- Digital Media Marketing, Saint Augustine Church, Unley
- Social Media Marketing, South Australian Road Runners Club, Adelaide
- Economic Development for Northern Territory Aboriginals, UnitingCare Wesley, Adelaide
- Executive Board of Directors, Singapore American Association, Singapore
- Event Assistant, American Chamber of Commerce, Singapore